Esta lição 13 de Pimsleur Inglês 1.
Listen to this telephone conversation. Listen to this telephone
conversation. Hello, Mary, it's Jack.
Hello, Jack, how are you? Fine, thanks. What are you doing tonight,
Mary? Tonight? Yes, would you like to have dinner with
me at 6 o'clock? Thanks, but I'm going to have dinner with
Nancy. Would you like to have something to drink at the hotel later?
Yes, I would. At what time? At nine o'clock
or later at ten o'clock. All right, at ten o'clock
at the hotel. Goodbye, Mary. Nesta conversa
você ouviu a palavra doing que quer dizer vai fazer.
Listen again. Listen again.
Hello, Mary. It's Jack. Hello, Jack. How are
you? Fine, thanks. What are you doing tonight, Mary?
Tonight? Yes. Would you like to have dinner with me at 6
o'clock? Thanks, but I'm going to have dinner with Nancy.
Would you like to have something to drink at the hotel later? Yes, I would.
At what time? At 9 o'clock or later at 10
o'clock. All right, at 10 o'clock at the hotel. Goodbye,
Mary. Pergunte-me que horas são.
What time is it?
What time is it, please?
Diga-me, são onze horas.
It's eleven o'clock.
Eleven. Diga não,
são oito horas.
No, it's eight o'clock.
Eight. Você se lembra de
como se pergunta quanto custa?
How much is it?
Como se diz o número um em inglês?
One. One.
Diga um dólar.
One dollar.
Você não ouviu bem o que ela disse. Pergunte.
Quanto? How much?
How much?
Agora diga treze dólares.
Thirteen dollars.
Diga não doze.
No, twelve. Twelve.
Pergunte: Doze ou treze?
Twelve or thirteen?
Diga: Sinto muito, eu não entendo.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Ela diz, por favor escute.
Please listen.
Agora diga. Por favor, repita.
Please repeat.
Pergunte: Você gostaria de jantar comigo?
Would you like to have dinner with me?
Ou você gostaria de tomar um pouco de vinho?
Or would you like to have some wine?
Would you like to have some wine?
Pergunte quando hoje?
When today?
Ou amanhã, or tomorrow.
Chega hoje à noite,
tonight,
tonight. Chega amanhã
tomorrow night.
Pergunte: a que horas?
At what time?
Diga: às 6 horas ou às 7 horas?
At 6 o'clock or at 7 o'clock?
Pergunte: quando você gostaria de tomar um pouco de vinho?
When would you like to have some wine?
今天。Today.
今天。Diga, amanhã à noite não.
Not tomorrow night.
Eu não vou comer.
I'm not going to eat.
Eu não vou comer com você.
I'm not going to eat with you.
Eu não vou comer com você amanhã à noite.
I'm not going to eat with you tomorrow night.
Agora ela te diz enfaticamente, mas eu
gostaria de jantar com você hoje à noite.
Lembre-se de que quando uma pessoa fala enfaticamente, não se
utiliza a contração.
But I would like to have dinner with you tonight.
I would. I would like to have
dinner with you tonight.
Diga tudo bem. All right.
All right.
Agora você quer perguntar quanto você tem em dólares.
Primeiro em dólares. Listen and repeat.
In dollars.
In,
in,
in dollars.
Diga em dólares.
In dollars.
Pergunte quanto.
How much? How much?
Agora, quanto você tem em dólares? Listen and
repeat. How much do you have in dollars?
In dollars.
Have.
You have. How much
do you have?
How much do you have in dollars?
Pergunte: Quanto você tem em dólares?
Como se diz você tem em You have.
Pergunte-me outra vez quanto eu tenho em dólares.
How much do you have in dollars?
Tente dizer eu tenho.
I have.
Eu tenho catorze dólares. Listen and repeat.
I have fourteen dollars.
Fourteen.
Fourteen. I have
fourteen dollars.
O número catorze contém o número quatro, ao qual se junta
a terminação teen. Em inglês, os números de treze
a dezenove terminam com teen. Diga catorze.
Fourteen.
Agora tente dizer dezesseis.
Sixteen.
Pergunte: Você tem dezesseis dólares?
Do you have sixteen dollars?
Diga não, eu tenho treze dólares.
No, I have thirteen dollars.
Pergunte-me outra vez quanto eu tenho em dólares.
How much do you have in dollars?
How much
do you have in dollars?
Quanto você tem em reais? Listen and repeat.
How much do you have in reais?
Reais. Reais.
In reais. How much
do you have in reais?
Pergunte outra vez: Quanto você tem em reais?
How much do you have in reais?
Responda: Eu tenho 14 reais.
I have fourteen reais.
Eu tenho quinze dólares. Listen and repeat.
I have fifteen dollars.
Fifteen.
Pergunte-me quanto eu tenho em dólares.
How much
do you have in dollars?
Diga: 15 dólares.
Fifteen dollars.
E 14 reais.
And fourteen reais.
Fourteen.
Agora tente dizer eu não tenho.
I don't have.
Eu não tenho. 16 reais.
I don't have sixteen reais.
Sixteen reais.
Sem mudar a ordem das palavras, tente perguntar: Você não
tem dezesseis reais?
You don't have sixteen reais?
Usando o número, diga: eu tenho um dólar.
I have one dollar.
Você vai pagar por algo que comprou.
Pergunte quanto custa.
How much is it?
How much is it, ma'am?
Ela diz: Quinze dólares, senhor.
Fifteen dollars, sir.
Diga tudo bem.
All right.
Pergunte e em reais?
And in reais?
In reais?
Pergunte em reais quanto custa.
In reals, how much is it?
Ela diz eu não sei.
I don't know. Ela diz
catorze dólares, por favor.
Fourteen dollars, please.
Diga, eu tenho nove reais.
I have nine reais.
Diga doze.
Twelve.
Pergunte quanto.
How much?
How much is it,
ma'am?
Ela responde: em dólares são quinze dólares.
In dollars, it's fifteen dollars.
E em reais?
And in reais?
Ela diz: Eu não sei, senhor.
I don't know, sir.
Agora, como se diz eu não tenho dezesseis dólares?
I don't have sixteen dollars.
I don't have.
Diga, eu tenho catorze dólares.
I have fourteen dollars.
Diga, mais quinze não.
But not fifteen.
Diga tudo
bem, então catorze dólares.
All right, then fourteen dollars.
Then,
then. All right, then fourteen
dollars.
Num outro dia você está comprando um outro item.
Pergunte: Quanto custa?
How much is it?
São dez dólares.
Is it ten dollars?
Como ela te diz, não, onze dólares.
No, eleven dollars.
It's eleven dollars.
Agora ela vai adicionar um ou dois dólares ao preço.
Cada vez que ela te disser um número, adicione e diga o total.
It's eleven dollars and one dollar.
Twelve dollars.
It's twelve dollars.
Yes, twelve dollars and two dollars.
Fourteen dollars.
It's $14.
Yes, and $1, please.
$15.
It's $15.
Yes, $15 and one.
Sixteen dollars.
Now it's sixteen
dollars.
Yes, it's sixteen dollars. Do you have sixteen dollars?
Diga-lhe que sim. Você tem dezesseis dólares.
Yes, I have sixteen dollars.
Agora escute. Here's sixteen dollars.
Ele disse: Aqui estão dezesseis dólares.
Now imagine you and some friends are in
a restaurant in the United States. You're going to speak with the bartender.
Diga-me, sinto muito, eu não entendo.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Agora imagine que você e uns amigos estão no restaurante nos Estados
Unidos. Você vai falar com o barman. Listen.
Hello, what would you like to drink? Diga-lhe educadamente
que você gostaria de uma cerveja.
I'd like a beer, please.
A beer. How many
beers would you like? One beer or two beers?
Usando número, diga-lhe uma cerveja.
One beer.
One beer, please.
Okay, here's a beer. Pergunte ao barman quanto custa.
How much is it?
It's two dollars. Diga-lhe que você não tem dez dólares.
I don't have ten dollars.
Ten dollars.
Not ten, two. Not ten,
two. Diga-lhe que agora você entende.
Now I understand.
Oh, now I understand.
Diga-lhe que você tem sete dólares.
I have seven dollars.
Você vai oferecer para pagar pelas cervejas. Diga-lhe que
você gostaria de três cervejas.
I'd like three beers.
Agora tente a conversa outra vez. Depois que ele falar
com você, responda ao barman educadamente que você gostaria
de uma cerveja. Hello, what would you like to drink?
I'd like a beer, please.
How many beers would you like? One beer or two beers?
Diga-lhe uma cerveja.
One beer.
One beer, please.
OK, here's a beer. Pergunte ao barman quanto
custa. How much
is it? It's two dollars.
Diga-lhe que você não tem dez dólares.
I don't have ten dollars.
Not ten, two. Not ten,
two. Diga-lhe que agora você entende.
Now I understand.
Oh, now I understand.
Diga-lhe que você tem sete dólares.
I have seven dollars.
Diga-lhe que você gostaria de três cervejas.
I'd like three beers.
Nesta lição de inglês um se incluem exercícios de leitura.